woolworthsrewards.com.au 2018-09-03

# Woolworths Rewards

**Privacy Policy**

View our Privacy video here

Woolworths Rewards' privacy policy is the [Woolworths Group Privacy Policy](https://www.woolworthsgroup.com.au/page/privacy-policy/).

**Cookies Statement**

For details about our use of cookies, please see our [Cookies Statement](https://www.woolworths.com.au/Shop/Discover/about-us/cookies-statement).

**Collection Notice**

**Notification of collection of personal information about Woolworths Rewards Members and prospective members**

The purpose of this Collection Notice is to explain how we collect, use, store and disclose the personal information of Woolworths Rewards Members and prospective members.

The terms of this Collection Notice form part of the Terms and Conditions of your Woolworths Rewards Membership. By registering as a Member, or by utilising any Membership Facilities such as your card, or claiming any Member Benefit, you acknowledge and agree that we will collect, use, store and disclose your personal information in accordance with the terms of this Notice.

Terms not defined in this Collection Notice have the same meaning given to those terms in the Woolworths Rewards Terms and Conditions.

**Who we are and how to contact us:**

Woolworths Group Limited ABN 80 000 014 675. Woolworths Rewards Members can email us at [privacy@woolworths.com.au](mailto:privacy@woolworths.com.au), write to us at Privacy Contact, Woolworths Group Limited, 1 Woolworths Way, Bella Vista NSW 2153 or call our contact centre on 1300 908 631 (our lines are open Monday to Friday 8:00am to 5:00pm Sydney time, excluding public holidays).

**Collection from Members:**

We collect personal information directly from you when you register to become a Member of Woolworths Rewards. This information is collected on our Registration form and includes your name, contact details and date of birth. Some of the information we collect on the Registration form is necessary to open a Woolworths Rewards account. If applicants for Membership choose not to provide this mandatory information, we will not be able to register them as a Member.

If Woolworths Rewards Members do not permit us to collect the personal information needed by us to send them service-based communications (such as their email address) under the Woolworths Rewards program, their Woolworths Rewards Membership may be terminated.

We also collect personal information in the course of administering your Membership. This includes information about your shopping history (such as items purchased, the price of those items, the date of purchase, and the location of the store), and whether you have taken up any of our offers or rewards.

We collect this information when you scan your Woolworths Rewards card at Earn Businesses (including participating fuel outlets). We also collect Members' transaction history from the use of their payment card, which is matched to their Woolworths Rewards account.. Our systems render payment card numbers unreadable (through the use of cryptographic hashing or encryption algorithm) and replace it with a randomised token number, which protects such details from unauthorised access or disclosure.

Linking this token number with a Member's account enables us to collect the Member's transaction history even when they do not scan their Woolworths Rewards card at the point of sale. The collection of this information enables Woolworths to continue to provide Members with personalised and more engaging and relevant offers than they would otherwise receive.

For more information, please see our [Privacy Policy](https://www.woolworthsgroup.com.au/page/privacy-policy/).

**Cookies:**

We collect information about Woolworths Rewards Members through the use of digital technologies like cookies. Cookies allow us to collect information (including anonymised information and personal information) based on your use of a device (such as computer or mobile phone) about your interactions with online content, and your interests and preferences. We use this information to personalise your interactions with us and to facilitate tailored advertising by Woolworths and trusted third parties.

For more information, please see our [Cookies Statement](https://www.woolworths.com.au/Shop/Discover/about-us/cookies-statement).

**Collection from others:**

We collect personal information about Woolworths Rewards Members from other persons or entities. For example, we collect personal information for marketing purposes from other suppliers of goods or services who, like us, have an existing relationship with Woolworths Rewards Members. Such entities include our strategic partners, Earn Businesses, affiliated programs, suppliers of publicly available information and digital services used by Woolworths Rewards Members (including social media platforms).

For purposes other than marketing, we collect personal information from persons and entities that assist or partner with us in supplying our goods and services to Woolworths Rewards Members, administering and improving the Woolworths Rewards program and conducting our business generally. These entities include insurers, providers of publicly available sources of information, delivery service companies, possible business sellers and buyers, third party data providers and our related bodies corporate.

At times, we combine different sets of data to add to the personal information we hold. An example of this is a history of a Member's transactions from use of the same payment card.

**Collection under a law or order:**

Many Australian laws authorise or require the collection of personal information about Woolworths Rewards Members. These include taxation laws, corporations law (for example relating to our shareholders), anti-money laundering laws and privacy laws. We may also collect personal information about Woolworths Rewards Members if we are required or authorised to do so by a court/tribunal order.

**Collection purposes:**

We collect personal information for the primary purposes of registering and administering a Member's account, to sell and promote products and services to you, to offer Member Benefits and Other Benefits, and to improve our customer offerings.

We do this by sending you:

direct marketing communications (including emails, or personalised catalogues); or

tailored advertising (including banner advertisements on websites that you visit,and personalised advertisements on social media platforms) about products and services that may interest you

We also use personal information to conduct product and market research, to seek customer feedback, for business improvement purposes, to keep our records accurate and up-to-date, and to respond to Members' enquiries and complaints.

Additionally, we anonymise or aggregate the personal information that we collect for the purpose of carrying out customer analytics. This helps us to understand our Members' preferences, interests, shopping patterns and behaviours so that we can improve and better administer the Woolworths Rewards program, and more effectively personalise the experience of our Members in promoting our goods and services.

We collect personal information for other purposes which are within Woolworths Rewards Members' reasonable expectations or permitted by law.

To manage Woolworths Rewards subscriptions or for information on opting out of direct marketing communications or tailored advertising, Members can log into their [Woolworths Rewards account](https://www.woolworthsrewards.com.au/) and review communication preferences on the Communications page under My account.

You can also opt out by using the unsubscribe/opt out facility in the communication that we send you. Opting-out of some of our communications means that we may not have access to the personal information we need to provide the Member Benefits or Other Benefits relevant to those opt-outs.

**Disclosure to others:**

We disclose the personal information we collect about Woolworths Rewards Members to other persons and entities.

For example, we disclose personal information to:

our service providers (including to our information technology and marketing service providers) to assist us in carrying out our functions and activities;

entities affiliated with the Woolworths Rewards program, which assist and support us in bringing you Member Benefits and Other Benefits;

to our related bodies corporate and to regulators or courts for compliance with the law or otherwise as legally appropriate.

We also disclose aggregated and anonymised information to our trusted partners (including our suppliers) about Woolworths Rewards Members' attributes, behaviours and preferences to enable them to market products and services that are likely to interest you based on those attributes, behaviours and preferences. This information is used to send you tailored or targeted advertising and is shared in a way that does not personally identify you. Such advertising may appear on the websites you visit in the form of banner advertisements, and/or on the social media sites you use.

You can opt out of receiving personalised offers. For information about how to opt out, please see your 'Communications Preferences' page on the Woolworths Rewards website.  

**Access and correction:**

The Woolworths Group Privacy Policy includes information about how Woolworths Rewards Members may access the personal information we hold about them and how they may seek correction of it. You can obtain a copy of our [Privacy Policy](https://www.woolworthsgroup.com.au/page/privacy-policy/), or by using the contact details provided above.

**Complaints:**

Our privacy policy contains information about how individuals, including Woolworths Rewards Members, may complain about a breach of the Australian Privacy Principles and any registered APP code that binds us. It also contains information about how we will deal with any such complaint.

**Overseas recipients:**

We are likely to disclose personal information about Woolworths Rewards members to overseas recipients. Our privacy policy provides information about the countries in which such recipients are likely to be located.

**Supplementary Collection Notice: Apple Wallet and Google Pay TM**

This Notice explains how Woolworths Group Limited (ABN 88 000 014 675) ("Woolworths", "we" or "our") collects, uses and discloses your personal information if you register and use your Woolworths Rewards card in Apple Wallet or Google Pay. The terms of this Notice apply in addition to the Woolworths Rewards Privacy Collection Notice (set out above), which applies generally to our handling of personal information for the purposes of the Woolworths Rewards program.

If you register and use your Woolworths Rewards card in Apple Wallet or Google Pay, Woolworths will collect personal information such as your name, address, contact details, demographic information, and information relating to your mobile device (including your device type and model, and operating system). We may disclose your details including your Rewards balance to Google which may use or disclosure this information for commercial purposes in accordance with its terms of service from time to time. We may also collect feedback about your use of Apple Wallet and Google Pay to help us better understand and improve the experience for our members.

We will send service and marketing-related notifications to your device. If you have Locations Services turned on in your Settings, you will also receive notifications based on the location of your device. For example, we may send you special offers if we identify that your device is in, or near, a Woolworths supermarket.

You can opt out from allowing Woolworths to send you these push notifications, or location-based notifications, by adjusting the permissions in your device Settings. Please note that these notification settings are for your device only and are independent of, and separate to, the marketing and communication settings in your Woolworths Rewards account.

We may share personal and anonymised information with Apple or Google and other service providers for commercial purposes and also in order for us to facilitate the use of your Woolworths Rewards card with Apple Wallet and Google Pay.

If you do not want us to collect, use or disclose the information described above, you should not register your Woolworths Rewards card in Apple Wallet or Google Pay.

In addition to this Notice, you should read

Apple's Privacy Policy at [www.apple.com/au/privacy](http://www.apple.com/au/privacy). If you register your card in Apple Wallet, Apple may access information about the use of your card.

Google's Privacy Policy at <https://policies.google.com/privacy>. If you register your card in Google Pay, Google may access information about you and the use of your card.

**Changes to this Collection Notice:**

We may change the terms of this Collection Notice from time to time. A copy of the revised Collection Notice will be available on the Website or can be obtained by calling the Contact Centre.

**Last updated:** May 2018.
